

Profile

My varied experiences over the last 10+ years in Chicago I.T. have equipped me with a versatile toolkit, which I leverage when tackling new problems or acquiring new skills. I am humble, service-minded and constantly striving to expand my knowledge and experiences.

Employment History

Programmer III / IT Analyst, East Carolina University, Chicago, IL (Remote)

NOVEMBER 2022

Designing, developing and maintaining a variety of enterprise-wide internet applications housed in the university's web portal. Additional duties include:

- Managing projects / functioning as a project technical lead
- · Developing specifications
- Code testing
- · Peer code reviews
- System analysis
- Troubleshooting & maintenance + issue resolution

Senior Application Support Analyst, American Hospital Association, Chicago, IL

JANUARY 2019 - JULY 2022

- Writing/maintaining complex T-SQL stored procedures/functions
- API development and design
- Building/maintaining functionality of AHA's storefront and all proximal systems
- Leading projects in the role of project manager/technical lead
- Authoring and maintaining detailed database and API documentation
- Participating in change control processes
- Providing advanced tier-4 support to end-users

Web Developer, BPOE USA, Chicago, IL

SEPTEMBER 2015 - JANUARY 2019

- Building and maintaining large-scale applications for membership management (PHP, ColdFusion)
- · Refactoring and modernizing old code
- User interface design and front-end development
- Developing wireframes / prototypes for new website functionality
- Supporting BPOE systems and users at all support tiers
- Print / email design

Director, Technical Support, NeonCRM, Chicago, IL

JUNE 2009 - DECEMBER 2013

- Building utilities for analyzing internal performance, peak submission times, resolution cycles
- Deep usage of issue resolution and tracking software (ZenDesk, JIRA)
- Extensive technical consulting and client management

Details

773.512.7765
patrickjdalton1@gmail.com

Skills

HTML5 / CSS3

Angular

React

ES₆

PHP (Drupal, CakePHP)

SQL (MySQL, T-SQL, SSRS)

REST/SOAP

Testing Frameworks (Jest, Mocha)

Prototyping

NoSQL (Mongo)

Templating Engines (Mustache, Handlebars, EJS, Jade)

Git

Troubleshooting / Debugging

Bash scripting

JIRA / ZenDesk

Microsoft IIS

C# .NET

ColdFusion

Postman

Package Managers (NPM, Yarn)

- Developing customer retention strategies
- Proposing new approaches to problems based on data-driven insights and discoveries
- Managing a team of support agents

Education

Software Development, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL

SEPTEMBER 2020 - MARCH 2021

Concordia University, River Forest, IL

AUGUST 2006 - AUGUST 2009